Draper Corporation Photographs 6612 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Contact prints from glass plate negatives, Series A:621-660: box no. 37-38, black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Contact prints from glass plate negatives, Series A:661-700: box no. 39-40, black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Contact prints from glass plate negatives, Series A:701-740: box no. 41-42, black and white photograph (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Contact prints from glass plate negatives, Series A:741-780: box no. 43-44, black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Contact prints from glass plate negatives, Series A:781-820: box no. 45-46, black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Item 804: Hurdle race, 1916; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A804. August 12, 1916. Image depicts a runner participating in a hurdle race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. One man has just cleared one of the hurdles, while another can be seen on the left approaching the hurdles. Another runner is just behind the man in the center, having just cleared the prior hurdle. Scattered spectators watch the race. See also Item 816 and Item 817, in this folder. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 805: Relay race finish (?), 1916; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A805. August 12, 1916. Image depicts a runner participating in a relay race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. The male runner appears to be about to break the string being held across the course at the finish line. No other runners are in sight. Spectators line the side of the course and some men in straw hats with their backs to the camera are on the right (possibly race officials). 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 809: Sack race, 1916; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A809. August 12, 1916. Image depicts six men participating in a sack race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. All of the men are in sacks up to their necks, as they hop along, trying to finish. Spectators look on in the background. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 811: Girls race, 1916; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A811. August 12, 1916. Image depicts a group of girls (well over a dozen) participating in a race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. Some spectators can be glimpsed in the background. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 812: Men's potato race, 1916; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A812. August 12, 1916. Image depicts a group of men participating in a potato race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. The idea is probably to be the first to fill your box (seen on the ground on the left) with potatoes. Most of the potato races at Draper Company events involved women or girls, but this one features men. Some spectators can be glimpsed in the background. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 814: Start of quarter-mile race, 1916; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A814. August 12, 1916. Image depicts a group of men participating in the quarter-mile race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. Six men leap forward from the start line for the race. Spectators look on from the left; note the parasols some of the women hold. The man at the far right and the man at the far left are probably race officials. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 815: Participants in relay race, 1916; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A815. August 12, 1916. Image depicts men participating in a relay race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. One man hands off to his partner in the center. Another runner is to the left, while a fourth man can be seen racing in the background. Spectators line the course on from the left; note the parasols some of the women hold. The men at the far right are probably race officials. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 816: Hurdle race, 1916; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A816. August 12, 1916. Image depicts runners participating in a hurdle race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. One man has just cleared one of the hurdles in the center right, while another leaps toward a hurdle on the left. A third runner can be seen racing up to the hurdles. Scattered spectators watch the race. See also Item 804 and Item 817, in this folder. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 817: Hurdle race, 1916; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A817. August 12, 1916. Image depicts runners participating in a hurdle race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. One man has just cleared one of the hurdles on the far left while another approaches on the left. Two more runners approach the hurdles in the center. The men on either side of the course in straw hats and jackets are probably race officials. A few scattered spectators watch in the background. See also Item 804 and Item 816, in this folder. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 818: Broad jump, 1916; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A818. August 12, 1916. Image depicts a participant in a broad jump contest, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. The jumper has just landed and an official stands by to measure his jump, while other officials look on. Spectators watch in the background. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 819: Race finish, 1916; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A819. August 12, 1916. Image depicts runners finishing a race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. It is unknown which race it is, but the man on the left in the dark shirt raises his arms in triumph as he hits the line being held at the finish line. Another runner matches him stride for stride, while two more runners can be seen further back. A crowd of spectators watches from the side of the course on the left. The man in the dark shirt can also be seen in Item 823, in this folder. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 820: Race participants, 1916; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A820. August 12, 1916. Image depicts five male runners participating in a race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. It is unknown which race it is, but the men are charging forward. A crowd of spectators watches from the side of the course on the left; note the number of parasols being held by some women. 25 x 20.25 cm.
- Contact prints from glass plate negatives, Series A:821-860: box no. 47-48, black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Contact prints from glass plate negatives, Series A:861-900: box no. 49-50, black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Contact prints from glass plate negatives, Series A:901-940: box no. 51-52, black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Item 901: Shop Dept. - Wet Hose competition, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A901. August 9, 1919. Image depicts two men, presumably employees of the Draper Corporation shop dept., handling a wet hose as part of some sort of competition, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. The man in the straw hat, kneeling behind the competitors, is an official of some kind. Spectators (mostly young boys) look on behind. See also Item 912, in this folder. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 902: Lawn tennis doubles, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A902. August 9, 1919. Image depicts men playing doubles tennis, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Two men are in the far court (one is in the backcourt, in the extreme left background) and a third man is in the near court. The fourth player is presumably out of camera range on the right. Some spectators watch from the far side of the court in the background. See also Item 903, Item 917, and Item 921, in this folder. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 903: Lawn tennis doubles, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A903. August 9, 1919. Image depicts men playing doubles tennis, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Two men are in the far court (one is in the backcourt, in the left background) and a third man is in the near court. The fourth player is presumably out of camera range on the right. The man in the near court has his right arm pulled back, about to return the ball. Some spectators watch from the far side of the court in the background. See also Item 902, Item 917, and Item 921, in this folder. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 904: Woman throwing baseball, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A904. August 9, 1919. Image depicts a woman throwing a baseball in front of a crowd, most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The woman is wearing a white dress, white stockings and white shoes, and is hatless. All of the spectators in the background are boys and men, including one man in a baseball uniform, and one man in a police uniform. See also Item 905 and Item 906, in this folder. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 905: Woman throwing baseball, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A905. August 9, 1919. Image depicts a woman throwing a baseball in front of a crowd, most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The woman is wearing a medium-colored dress with a white collar and white cuffs, dark stockings and shoes, and is wearing a straw hat. She is wearing a necklace and rimless glasses. All of the spectators in the background are boys and men, including two men in baseball uniforms. See also Item 904 and Item 906, in this folder. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 906: Woman throwing baseball, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A906. August 9, 1919. Image depicts a woman throwing a baseball in front of a crowd, most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The woman is wearing a white dress with a "sailor" collar, white stockings and shoes, and a white cloche hat. All of the spectators in the background are boys and men, including one man in a baseball uniform and one man in a policeman's uniform. See also Item 904 and Item 905, in this folder. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 907: Participant in shot-put competition, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A907. August 9, 1919. Image depicts a man participating in a shot-put competition, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The man has just hurled the shot-put out of camera range. The man in the straw hat on the extreme left and the man in the white shirt standing behind the competitor are both officials of some kind. Male and female spectators line the side of the field. See also Item 908, in this folder, which shows a different competitor. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 908: Participant in shot-put competition, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A908. August 9, 1919. Image depicts a man participating in a shot-put competition, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The man (in the foreground) has just hurled the shot-put out of camera range. The man in the straw hat on the extreme left, the man in the white shirt standing in the center behind the competitor, and the man in suit and tie with a straw hat next to him are all officials of some kind. Another competitor stands to wait his turn. Male and female spectators line the side of the field in the background. See also Item 907, in this folder, which shows a different competitor. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 909: Start of the 220-yard dash, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A909. August 9, 1919. Image depicts male runners at the start of the 220-yard dash, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Eight men burst forth from the starting line in the foreground. An official of some sort stands behind them. Spectators, both men and women, line the side of the course. See also, Item 926, in this folder. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 910: Finish of half-mile race, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A910. August 9, 1919. Image depicts male runner finishing the half-mile race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The male runner is just crossing the finish line; no other runners are in sight. Spectators, both men and women, line the side of the course. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 911: Fire Dept. relay race, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A911. August 9, 1919. Image depicts two male runners handing off a baton in the Fire Dept. relay race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. It is presumed that these are members of the fire dept. of the Draper Corporation and not the Hopedale Fire Dept., but it is possible that town employees competed against Draper Corp. employees. The man with his back to the camera, behind the runner, is most likely an official. Spectators, both men and women, line the side of the course. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 912: Shop Dept.: Wet Hose competition, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A912. August 9, 1919. Image depicts two men, presumably employees of the Draper Corporation shop dept., handling a wet hose as part of some sort of competition, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Spectators (mostly young boys) look on behind. See also Item 901, in this folder, but the men seem to have a better grip on the hose in this image. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 913: Shop Dept. relay race, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A913. August 9, 1919. Image depicts two male runners on the left handing off a baton in the Draper Corporation shop dept. relay race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. In the center, another runner waits for his relay partner to arrive. A fourth runner is off to the side on the right. Spectators, both men and women, line the side of the course. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 914: 50-yard girls' race, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A914. August 9, 1919. Image depicts a group of girls taking part in the 50-yard girls' race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Some spectators can be seen in the background. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 915: Finish, 100-yard dash, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A915. August 9, 1919. Image depicts the finish of the 100-yard dash that took place, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Several men race to the finish line, with two crossing the line at approximately the same spot; two more men are behind them. Spectators line the race course, mostly men near the finish but many ladies can be seen further away. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 916: Town Dept.: Wet Hose competition, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A916. August 9, 1919. Image depicts two men handling a wet hose as part of some sort of competition, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The man in the straw hat, kneeling off to the right, is an official of some kind (he is also seen in Item 901). Spectators (mostly young boys) look on behind. It is unclear if "town dept." refers to a dept. of some sort in the Draper Corporation, or whether these were town employees competing against Draper employees--see Item 901, in this folder, for the "Shop Dept." participating in the same competition. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 917: Lawn tennis doubles, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A917. August 9, 1919. Image depicts men playing doubles tennis, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Two of the men are in the far court (one close to the net, the other in the back court), while one man is positioned in the near court, close to the net. The fourth player is not visible but may be in the backcourt on the right out of the photographer's range. Spectators watch from the sidelines in the background. See also Item 902, Item 903, and Item 921, in this folder. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 918: Spoon and Potato Race, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A918. August 9, 1919. Image depicts three women participating in a spoon and potato race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The general idea is presumably to be the first to get your potato to a designated area (probably the boxes on the far left) and whichever box fills first wins the race. A crowd of spectators watches in the background. This does not appear to be the same race as the girls' potato race, shown in Item 919 and Item 920. See also Item 923, in this folder. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 919: Girls Potato Race, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A919. August 9, 1919. Image depicts a number of young girls participating in a potato race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. There is a line of boxes on the ground in the left foreground; the object is probably for your team to fill your box with potatoes and whichever box is filled first get the prize. A crowd of spectators watches in the background. It does not appear as if the girls were using spoons to carry the potatoes, as seen in Item 918, but it is unclear. The men on the left in the straw hats are probably monitoring the boxes. See also Item 920, in this folder. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 920: Girls Potato Race, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A920. August 9, 1919. Image depicts a number of young girls participating in a potato race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. There is a line of boxes on the ground in the left foreground; the object is probably for your team to fill your box with potatoes and whichever box is filled first get the prize. A crowd of spectators watches in the background. It does not appear as if the girls were using spoons to carry the potatoes, as seen in Item 918, but it is unclear. The men on the left in the straw hats are probably monitoring the boxes. See also Item 919, in this folder. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 921: Lawn tennis doubles, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A921. August 9, 1919. Image depicts men playing doubles tennis, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Two of the men are in the far court, while one leaps into the air to hit an overhand shot in the near court. The fourth player is not visible but may be in the backcourt on the right out of the photographer's range. A number of spectators line the court in the background. See also Item 902, Item 903, and Item 917, in this folder. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 922: Start of relay race, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A922. August 9, 1919. Image depicts two men at the start of a relay race that took place, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Two men have just taken off from starting positions in the foreground, with many spectators lined up beside the course stretching into the background. Spectators include both men and women. An official of some sort stands just behind the two runners. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 923: Spoon and potato race, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A923. August 9, 1919. Image depicts several women participating in a spoon and potato race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The general idea is presumably to be the first to get your potato to the boxes on the far left and whichever box is filled first wins the race. A crowd of spectators watches in the background. This does not appear to be the same race as the girls' potato race, shown in Item 919 and Item 920, in this folder. See also Item 918, in this folder. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 924: Start of 1/4-mile race, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A924. August 9, 1919. Image depicts six men racing at the start of the 1/4-mile race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The two men in suits standing behind the runners are probably officials. Spectators watch from the side of the course. See also, Item 925, in this folder. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 925: Finish of 1/4-mile race, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A925. August 9, 1919. Image depicts one man crossing the finish line of the 1/4-mile race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The man (with his arms raised) has just crossed the finish line; two more runners can be seen behind him. Spectators watch from the side of the course. See also, Item 926, in this folder. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 926: Finish of 220-yard dash, 1919; black and white photograph (Box 5, Folder 5)